<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ContextHelp version="0.x" Author="Kurtnoise, Zathor et all" LastUpdated="20XX-XX-XX">
	<Codec name="x264">
		<slicesnb name="Slices">
			<Text>
Sets the number of slices per frame, and forces rectangular slices.
(Overridden by either --slice-max-size or --slice-max-mbs if they are set.)
If you are encoding for Blu-ray, set this to four. 
Otherwise, don't use this unless you know you need to.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0 (4 for Blu-ray)</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</slicesnb>
		<maxSliceSizeBytes name="--slice-max-size">
			<Text>
Limit the size of each slice in bytes
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</maxSliceSizeBytes>
		<maxSliceSizeMB name="--slice-max-mbs">
			<Text>
Limit the size of each slice in macroblocks
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</maxSliceSizeMB>
		<gopcalculation name="GOP Calculation">
			<Text>
Determines how minimum and maximum GOP size are calculated.

Fixed: 
the selected values will be used

FPS based: 
the values will be used as on a 25 FPS basis
Maximum/Minimum value is divided by 25 * actual FPS
e.g. 250 / 25fps * 23.967fps = 240
			</Text>
			<Recommended>FPS based</Recommended>
			<Default>FPS based</Default>
		</gopcalculation>
		<opengop name="Open GOPs">
			<Text>
Use recovery points to close GOPs. Only available with b-frames.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>disabled</Default>
		</opengop>
		<encodingmode name="Encoding Mode">
			<Text>
Defines the desired encoding mode.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Const. Quality</Recommended>
			<Default>Const. Quality</Default>
		</encodingmode>
		<device name="Target Playback Device">
			<Text>
Defines the desired playback device. Based upon the setting some parameters are enforced/restricted.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Your desired playback device</Recommended>
			<Default>Default</Default>
		</device>
		<keyint name="Maximum Key Frame Interval">
			<Text>
Defines the maximum size of a Group of Pictures. A frame in a GOP cannot reference
frames in other GOPs, and in doing so enables seeking and random access. GOP sizes
are dynamically calculated during encoding to maximise compression, however specifying
a maximum GOP prevents any reduction of seekability.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>250</Recommended>
			<Default>250</Default>
		</keyint>
		<min-keyint name="Minimum Key Frame Interval">
			<Text>
Defines the minimum size of a Group of Pictures. A frame in a GOP cannot reference
frames in other GOPs, and in doing so enables seeking and random access.
GOP sizes are dynamically calculated during encoding to maximise compression,
however specifying a minimum GOP will help improve compression in high motion scenes.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>25</Recommended>
			<Default>25</Default>
		</min-keyint>
		<scenecut name="Scene Change Sensitivity">
			<Text>
Modifies the sensitivity to scene changes. Scene change detection is useful as it forces
the use of an I-frame at a scene change, leading to better looking cuts and overall
improvement in quality.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>40</Recommended>
			<Default>40</Default>
		</scenecut>
		<bframes name="Maximum B-frames">
			<Text>
Bi-directional Predictive Frames are highly compressed as they only store the data that
has changed from the previous frame or that is different from the next frame. B-frames
generally have less quality than I- or P- frames but can increase the overall quality of the
video by storing data very efficiently. A setting of 2 to 3 will usually provide a good
overall quality while allowing significant compression advantages.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>2 to 3</Recommended>
			<Default>3</Default>
		</bframes>
		<b-adapt name="Adaptive B-frames">
			<Text>
Enables x264 to make adaptive decisions on where B-frames should be used, decreasing
the number of consecutive B-frames where it makes sense.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>1 - Fast</Recommended>
			<Default>1 - Fast</Default>
		</b-adapt>
		<b-bias name="B-frame Bias">
			<Text>
Positive values increase the likelihood that a B-frame will be used, negative values decrease
the likelihood, without violating the "Maximum B-frames" setting.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</b-bias>
		<b-pyramid name="B-frame Pyramid">
			<Text>
Allows B-frames to be used as references for other B-frames, increasing compression efficiency
when 2 or more B-frames are used. 3 modes available : None = Disabled, Strict = Strictly Hierarchical Pyramid,
Normal = Non-Strict (not Blu-ray compatible)
			</Text>
			<Recommended>normal</Recommended>
			<Default>normal</Default>
		</b-pyramid>
		<slow-firstpass name="Slow first pass">
			<Text>
With the advent of the Preset system in r1177, using --pass 1 applies the following settings at the end of parsing the command line:
* ref 1
* no-8x8dct
* partitions i4x4 (if originally enabled, else none)
* me dia
* subme MIN( 2, subme )
* trellis 0
This feature is automatically disabled with preset placebo. To otherwise disable the feature, uncheck this option.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>disabled</Default>
		</slow-firstpass>
		<!--WARNING DOUBLE NEGATIVE-->
		<no-cabac name="Encode CABAC">
			<Text>
CABAC is a clever technique of losslessly compressing the syntax elements of the video
stream, knowing the probabilities of the elements in a given context. CABAC uses more
CPU for encoding and decoding. When disabled, video is encoded using CAVLC (Context
Adaptive Variable Length Encoding) which is less CPU intensive but provides less compression.
Note: Some advanced features will not be available when encoding with CAVLC.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Enabled</Default>
		</no-cabac>
		<ref name="Reference Frames">
			<Text>
Determines how many previous frames can be referenced by a P- or B-frame. Encoding slows
as more frames are used. The maximum value is 16, however quality increases become marginal
with more than 5 reference frames.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>1 to 5</Recommended>
			<Default>3</Default>
		</ref>
		<nf name="Deblocking (in loop) Filter">
			<Text>
MPEG-4 AVC defines video with a grid of squares representing moving data, the in loop deblocking
filter detects the edges of these squares in order to smooth them. In loop deblocking is part of the
normal operation of MPEG-4 AVC and should not be disabled.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Enabled</Default>
		</nf>
		<filter name="Deblocking (in loop) Filter Strength">
			<Text>
Deblocking strength is computed for each macroblock according to the quantizer of the macroblock
and that of its neighbours. Alpha is used to determine whether the frontier of an encoded macroblock
is blocky or if it's actually a detail. It works like a threshold. Beta also works like a threshold, but is
used to insure that the picture is homogenous on both sides of the frontier in order to separate detail
from blockiness. When blocks are detected, alpha is used to decide the strength (maximum allowed
modification of the pixel). Beta applies slight modification to this strength if the macroblock is homogenous. 
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0:0</Recommended>
			<Default>0:0</Default>
		</filter>
		<!--Rate control options:-->
		<qp name="Constant Quantizer">
			<Text>
Set x264 to encode in Constant Quantizer mode. The number you give here specifies the P-frame quantizer.
The quantizer used for I- and B-frames is derived from ipratio and pbratio. 
CQ mode targets a certain quantizer, which means final filesize is not known 
(although it can be reasonably accurately estimated with some methods). A setting of 0 will produce lossless output.
qp produces larger files than crf for the same visual quality. qp mode also disables adaptive quantization,
since by definition 'constant quantizer' implies no adaptive quantization.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>21 to 28</Recommended>
			<Default>23</Default>
		</qp>
		<bitrate name="Average Bit Rate">
			<Text>
Encode the video in target bitrate mode. x264 will attempt to encode the video to target the given bitrate 
as the final average. The parameter given is the bitrate in kilobits/sec. (8bits = 1byte and so on). 
This setting is usually used in conjunction with pass for two-pass encoding. Target bitrate mode means 
the final filesize is known, but the final quality is not (although it's possible to estimate with a reasonable
degree of accuracy). It is generally not recommended to use bitrate mode without 2pass encoding.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>N/A</Recommended>
			<Default>N/A</Default>
		</bitrate>
		<crf name="Constant Ratefactor">
			<Text>
CRF targets a certain 'quality'. The idea is for crf n to give the same perceptual quality as qp n, 
just in a smaller space. It is not extremely exact, but reasonably close (and will average out to be 
accurate over a large number of videos). The arbitrary unit of measure for crf values is the "ratefactor".
CRF achieves this by reducing the quality of 'less important' frames. In this context, 'less important' means
frames in complex or high-motion scenes, where quality is either more expensive (in terms of bits) 
or less visible, will have their quantizer increased. The bits saved in frames like these are redistributed 
to frames where they will be more effective. CRF will take less time than a 2pass bitrate encode, 
because the 'first pass' from a 2pass encode was skipped. On the other hand, it's impossible to predict 
the bitrate a CRF encode will come out to (without actually performing the encode or a portion of it). 
It's up to you to decide which rate-control mode is better for your circumstances.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>The range 18-26 is probably where you will want to look at. If you need absolutely perfect quality 
		you could go down to 16, but it's probably not worth it. Around 19-21.5 is where an encoding will look very good. 
		Higher resolution encoding can generally get away with higher crf values.</Recommended>
			<Default>23</Default>
		</crf>
		<qpmin name="Minimum Quantizer">
			<Text>
Enforces a minimum Quantizer. Prevents the codec from outputting frames with too little
compression, wasting bits. Note: This is disregarded in Constant Quality or Quality Based VBR modes.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</qpmin>
		<qpmax name="Maximum Quantizer">
			<Text>
Enforces a maximum Quantizer. Prevents the codec from outputting frames with too much compression,
causing reduced quality. Note: This is disregarded in Constant Quality or Quality Based VBR modes.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>69</Recommended>
			<Default>69</Default>
		</qpmax>
		<qpstep name="Maximum Quantizer Steps">
			<Text>
Sets how much the quantizer can change between consecutive frames, maintaining a more stable
level of quality.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>4</Recommended>
			<Default>4</Default>
		</qpstep>
		<ratetol name="Average Bit rate Variance (%)">
			<Text>
Regulates how much the bit rate can fluctuate from the target Average Bit Rate that has
been set. Lower settings constrict bit rate changes, producing a file that will stream better
and more closely match a predicted file size based on the set bit rate, while reducing the
codec's ability to adapt to complex scenes. Higher settings increase bit rate variability which
decreases the reliability of streaming and the ability to predict the file size, while improving
the codec's ability to adapt to complex scenes. Setting this to 0% would result in a constant
bit rate. Setting this to 100% would provide a highly erratic bit rate dependant on scene
complexity. (A setting of 100% would result in Constant Quantizer compression.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>1.0 to 4.0</Recommended>
			<Default>1.0</Default>
		</ratetol>
		<vbv-maxrate name="VBV Maximum Bit rate">
			<Text>
Specifies the maximum bit rate allowed in the Video Buffer.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Depends on the selected AVC level and profile. If value is shown in red playback may be affected - reselect AVC level/profile or target playback device to set the proper value.</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</vbv-maxrate>
		<vbv-bufsize name="VBV Buffer Size">
			<Text>
Specifies the maximum size of the Video Buffer, which can affect playback start up times
if too large and cause stuttering if too small.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Depends on the selected AVC level and profile. If value is shown in red playback may be affected - reselect AVC level/profile or target playback device to set the proper value.</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</vbv-bufsize>
		<vbv-init name="VBV Initial Size">
			<Text>
Specifies the level of the Video Buffer to fill before playback can begin. Low levels may
cause reduced initial quality while high levels may cause artificially high initial quality.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0.9</Recommended>
			<Default>0.9</Default>
		</vbv-init>
		<ipratio name="I-P Quantizer Factor">
			<Text>
Specifies the level of quality reduction between high quality I-frames and the more
compressed P-frames that follow.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>1.4</Recommended>
			<Default>1.4</Default>
		</ipratio>
		<pbratio name="P-B Quantizer Factor">
			<Text>
Specifies the level of quality reduction between P-frames and the more compressed B-frames that follow.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>1.3</Recommended>
			<Default>1.3</Default>
		</pbratio>
		<chroma-qp-offset name="Chroma and Luma Quantizer Offset">
			<Text>
Specifies the level of quality reduction between colour and brightness information.
The human eye is more sensitive to changes in brightness than colour, so compression
can be increased by removing some colour detail.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</chroma-qp-offset>
		<pass name="Multipass Mode">
			<Text>
Multiple passes allow the codec to make more informed choices when deciding how
to compress each frame in regards to the quality and complexity of the entire clip.
Note: 2 pass encoding will take up to twice as long.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</pass>
		<stats name="Statistics File Name">
			<Text>
This file holds information generated about each frame, which is then used to make
more informed choices on the finial pass.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>x264_2pass.stats</Recommended>
			<Default>x264_2pass.stats</Default>
		</stats>
		<qcomp name="Quantizer Curve Compression">
			<Text>
Regulates how much the quality can fluctuate within the target Average Bit Rate that
has been set. Higher settings constrict quality changes, producing a file that will have
a more constant quality throughout, while reducing the codec's ability to adapt to complex
scenes where loss of detail may not be as important. Lower settings increase variability
of quality, which may improve visual quality throughout the video by reducing quality
where fine detail can't be seen and increasing it where fine detail is more noticeable.
Setting this to 1 would result in constant quality. Setting this to 0 would create highly
erratic quality changes.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0.60</Recommended>
			<Default>0.60</Default>
		</qcomp>
		<cplxblur name="Quantizer Fluctuation Reduction (Before)">
			<Text>Reduce fluctuations in Quantizer (before curve compression).</Text>
			<Recommended>20.0</Recommended>
			<Default>20.0</Default>
		</cplxblur>
		<qblur name="Quantizer Fluctuation Reduction (After)">
			<Text>Reduce fluctuations in QP (after curve compression).</Text>
			<Recommended>0.5</Recommended>
			<Default>0.5</Default>
		</qblur>
		<zones name="Define Zones">
			<Text>
Zones allow you to define areas of video for which you can specify additional encoding
options. eg you may specify the credits at the end of the film to use a lower bit rate or
higher compression than the main feature.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</zones>
		<!--Analysis options:-->
		<analyse name="Macroblock Analysis Sizes">
			<Text>
Enabling additional macroblock search sizes increases encoding efficiency and quality
but decreases speed. Note: i8x8 can only be used in High Profile and when Adaptive
8x8 DCT is used.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>All (High Profile)</Recommended>
			<Default>p8x8,b8x8,i8x8,i4x4</Default>
		</analyse>
		<direct name="B-frame Mode">
			<Text>
Determines how motion vectors for B-frames are derived. Spatial uses neighbouring
blocks in the same frame which may result in higher PSNR. Temporal makes use of
neighbouring frames which may be perceived as higher quality. Auto selects direct
mode per frame. Works best in 2pass (enable in both passes).
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Spatial</Recommended>
			<Default>Spatial</Default>
		</direct>
		<weightb name="B-frame Weighted Prediction">
			<Text>
Enables 'brightness' weighting of B-frames which improves fades and colour gradients ie sky.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Enabled</Default>
		</weightb>
	<weightp name="P-frame Weighted Prediction">
		<Text>
Enables use of explicit weighted prediction to improve compression in P-frames. Higher modes are slower.
		</Text>
		<Recommended>2</Recommended>
		<Default>2</Default>
	</weightp>
		<me name="Motion Estimation Mode">
			<Text>
Controls the method used to search for motion vectors. Diamond search radius 1 (fastest),
 hexagonal search radius 2 (fast), uneven multi-hexagon search (slow), exhaustive search, hadamard exhaustive search
(slowest). Exhaustive search is not recommended for normal use as it is exceptionally slow
and does not provide significant quality increases.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>hexagonal</Recommended>
			<Default>hexagonal</Default>
		</me>
		<merange name="Maximum Motion Vector Range">
			<Text>
Specifies the maximum range a macroblock can travel in order to be encoded as a vector.
Larger values may increase efficiency but will increase encoding time.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>16 to 32</Recommended>
			<Default>16</Default>
		</merange>
		<subme name="Sub Pixel Refinement">
			<Text>
Controls the decision quality of motion estimation. Lower values will make faster and less
accurate decisions. Higher values will improve quality but will slow encoding speed.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>7</Recommended>
			<Default>7</Default>
		</subme>
		<mixed-refs name="No Mixed References">
			<Text>
Mixed refs will select refs on a per-8x8 partition, rather than per-macroblock basis. This improves quality when using multiple reference frames, albeit at some speed cost. Setting this option will disable it.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</mixed-refs>
		<!--WARNING DOUBLE NEGATIVE-->
		<no-chroma-me name="Chroma Motion Estimation">
			<Text>
Enables Motion Estimation to take colour components of the video into account when calculating movement, improving quality.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Enabled</Default>
		</no-chroma-me>
		<!--Note: name changed from 8x8dct due to invalid XML character warning-->
		<i8x8dct name="Adaptive 8x8 DCT">
			<Text>
Enables the intelligent adaptive use of 8x8 transforms in I-frames. Requires I8X8 checked.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Enabled</Default>
		</i8x8dct>
		<i4x4mv name="4x4 sub-partitions for I-Frames">
			<Text>
Enables the use of 4x4 sub-partitions in predicted macroblocks, for I-frames.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</i4x4mv>
		<p4x4mv name="4x4 sub-partitions for P-Frames">
			<Text>
Enables the use of 4x4 sub-partitions in predicted macroblocks, for P-frames. 
Improves compression by about 0.5%, at the cost of encoding speed. Requires P8X8 enabled.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</p4x4mv>
		<p8x8mv name="8x8 sub-partitions for P-Frames">
			<Text>
Enables the use of 8x8 sub-partitions in predicted macroblocks, for P-frames.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</p8x8mv>
		<b8x8mv name="8x8 sub-partitions for B-Frames">
			<Text>
Enables the use of 8x8 sub-partitions in predicted macroblocks, for B-frames.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</b8x8mv>
		<i8x8mv name="8x8 sub-partitions for I-Frames">
			<Text>
Enables the use of 8x8 sub-partitions in predicted macroblocks, for I-frames.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</i8x8mv>
		<trellis name="Trellis Quantization">
			<Text>
Performs Trellis quantization to increase efficiency. On Macroblock provides a
good compromise between speed and efficiency. On all decisions reduces
speed further.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>1 - Only on the final encode of a Macro Block</Recommended>
			<Default>Enabled</Default>
		</trellis>
		<psyrd name="Psychovisual RD optimizations">
			<Text>
Modifies the rate-distortion metric to improve sharpness and detail retention.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>1.0</Recommended>
			<Default>1.0</Default>
		</psyrd>
		<psytrellis name="Psychovisual Trellis optimizations">
			<Text>
Experimental: attempts to improve sharpness beyond that of the ordinary trellis algorithm.
Your mileage may vary.			
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0.0</Recommended>
			<Default>0.0</Default>
		</psytrellis>
		<mbtree name="MB-Tree Rate Control">
			<Text>
It tracks the propagation of information from future blocks to past blocks across motion vectors.
It could be described as localizing qcomp to act on individual blocks instead of whole scenes.
Thus instead of lowering quality in high-complexity scenes (like x264 currently does), it'll only
lower quality on the complex part of the scene, while for example a static background
will remain high-quality.
It also has many other more subtle effects, some potentially negative, most probably not.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Enabled</Default>
		</mbtree>
		<lookahead name="RC-Lookahead">
			<Text>
Sets the number of frames to use for mb-tree ratecontrol. 
Increasing the frame count generates better results but it's also slower. 
Maximum value is 250 or keyint, whichever is smaller.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>40-50</Recommended>
			<Default>40</Default>
		</lookahead>
		<!--WARNING DOUBLE NEGATIVE-->
		<no-fast-pskip name="Fast P-frame Skip Detection">
			<Text>
Fast Skip detection increases speed but may cause slight blockiness in areas
of solid colour or slight gradients such as dark scenes or sky.
Enabling this option will DISABLE the Fast Skip detection.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Enabled</Default>
		</no-fast-pskip>
		<nr name="Noise Reduction">
			<Text>
Estimates film noise based on this value and attempts to remove it by
dropping small details before quantization. This may not match the quality
of a good external noise reduction filter, but it performs very fast.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0 (100-1000 for denoising)</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</nr>
		<cqm name="Preset Quantization Matrices">
			<Text>Preset quantization matrices. (jvt, flat)</Text>
			<Recommended>Flat</Recommended>
			<Default>Flat</Default>
		</cqm>
		<cqmfile name="Quantization Matrice File">
			<Text>Read quantization matrices from a JM compatible file. (Overrides any other --cqm* options).</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</cqmfile>
		<cqm4 name="4x4 Quantization Matrices">
			<Text>
Takes a comma separated list of 16 integers.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</cqm4>
		<cqm8 name="8x8 Quantization Matrices">
			<Text>
Set all 8x8 quantization matrices.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</cqm8>
		<sar name="Sample Aspect Ratio">
			<Text>
Stores the size of non-square pixels in the video stream for use during playback. This enables anamorphic video.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>1:1</Recommended>
			<Default>1:1</Default>
		</sar>
		<!--Video Usability options:-->
		<level name="AVC Complexity Level">
			<Text>Specify level (as defined by Annex A)</Text>
			<Recommended>Unrestricted/AutGuess</Recommended>
			<Default>Unrestricted/AutoGuess</Default>
		</level>
		<fps name="Frame Rate">
			<Text>
This can be used to change the frame rate of the video during encoding
(or specify the frame rate for a source that does not detect correctly).
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Automatic</Recommended>
			<Default>Automatic</Default>
		</fps>
		<seek name="Seek to Start Frame">
			<Text>Enables encoding to begin at any point in the source.</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</seek>
		<frames name="Frames to Encode">
			<Text>Enables encoding to finish at a point before the end of the source.</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</frames>
		<output name="Output File Name">
			<Text>Specify output file</Text>
			<Recommended></Recommended>
			<Default></Default>
		</output>
		<threads name="Number of Threads">
			<Text>
For optimum speed, this should be left at 0, ie automatic detection.
The automatic setting is 1.5 x logical CPUs. Threads increase encoding
speed and negligibly negatively affect quality.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>0 (auto)</Recommended>
			<Default>0 (auto)</Default>
		</threads>
		<!--WARNING DOUBLE NEGATIVE-->
		<no-asm name="CPU Optimizations">
			<Text>
Codecs use advanced CPU SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) instruction
sets allowing massive speed increases. This should only be enabled for
troubleshooting purposes.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</no-asm>
		<!--WARNING DOUBLE NEGATIVE-->
		<psnr name="PSNR Computation">
			<Text>
Prevents PSNR calculations that are reported on completion.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</psnr>
		<ssim name="SSIM Computation">
			<Text>
Prevents SSIM calculations that are reported on completion.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</ssim>
		<stitchable name="Stitch able">
			<Text>
Ensures ability to recombine a segmented encode
Don't optimize headers based on video content
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Enabled if you want to merge video files</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</stitchable>
		<quiet name="Quiet Mode">
			<Text>Enable Quiet Mode (do not display output information).</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</quiet>
		<verbose name="Verbose Mode">
			<Text>Show frame statistics.</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</verbose>
		<progress name="Progress Meter">
			<Text>Show a progress indicator while encoding.</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</progress>
		<visualize name="Visualize Analysis">
			<Text>
Debugging option used to understand what is happening on a frame by frame basis.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</visualize>
		<aud name="Access Unit Delimiters">
			<Text>
Use access unit delimiters
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled, unless encoding for Blu-ray, in which case set this option</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</aud>
		<nalhrd name="nal-hrd">
			<Text>
Add NAL HRD parameters to the output stream; used for HD-DVD and Blu-ray compliancy. 
Depends on vbv-bufsize and vbv-maxrate to be set to be active. 
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Disabled, unless encoding for Blu-ray, in which case set this option</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</nalhrd>
		<customcommandline name="Custom command line">
			<Text>
The parameters specified in the custom command line will overwrite the parameters specified in the GUI.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Empty, unless some parameters have to be forced</Recommended>
			<Default>Empty</Default>
		</customcommandline>
		<aqmode name="AQ Mode">
			<Text>
This option controls how AQ distributes bits. Mode 0 disables the feature whereas 
Mode 1 enables Variance AQ (complexity mask) and Mode 2 enables Auto-Variance AQ (still experimental)
			</Text>
			<Recommended>1</Recommended>
			<Default>1</Default>
		</aqmode>
		<aqstrength name="AQ Strength">
			<Text>
Reduces blocking and blurring in flat and textured areas. To have a weak AQ choose 0.5
and a strong one 1.5 as value.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>1.0</Recommended>
			<Default>1.0</Default>
		</aqstrength>
		<creditsquant name="Credits Quantizer">
			<Text>
Applies this constant quantizer to the selected zones
			</Text>
			<Recommended></Recommended>
			<Default>40</Default>
		</creditsquant>
		<profile name="AVC Profiles">
			<Text>
The H.264 standard includes the following sets of capabilities, which are referred to as profiles,
targeting specific classes of applications:
- Baseline Profile (BP): Primarily for lower-cost applications with limited computing resources,
	this profile is used widely in videoconferencing and mobile applications.
- Main Profile (MP): Originally intended as the mainstream consumer profile for broadcast and
	storage applications, the importance of this profile faded when the High profile was 
	developed for those applications.
- Extended Profile (XP): Intended as the streaming video profile, this profile has relatively high
	compression capability and some extra tricks for robustness to data losses and server stream switching.
- High Profile (HiP): The primary profile for broadcast and disc storage applications, particularly
	for high-definition television applications (this is the profile adopted into HD DVD and Blu-ray Disc,
	for example).
			</Text>
			<Recommended>High Profile</Recommended>
			<Default>High Profile</Default>
		</profile>
		<tunes name="x264 Tunings">
			<Text>
Tune options to further optimise them for your input content. 
If you specify a tuning, the changes will be applied after 
a preset but before all other parameters.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>none</Recommended>
			<Default>none</Default>
		</tunes>
		<presets name="x264 Presets">
			<Text>
Change options to trade off compression efficiency and quality.
If you specify a preset, the changes it makes will be applied
before all other parameters are applied.
Faster presets will shorten the encoding time while
- lowering the quality in bitrate mode or
- increasing the file size in Constant Quantizer or Constant Ratefactor mode
			</Text>
			<Recommended>Medium</Recommended>
			<Default>Medium</Default>
		</presets>
		<targetmode name="Target mode">
			<Text>
If you need to reach a specific file size select "Targeting file size".
If not it is recommended to select "Targeting quality".
			</Text>
			<Recommended></Recommended>
			<Default></Default>
		</targetmode>
		<encoder10bit name="10bit Encoder">
			<Text>
10 bit encodings have a higher quality than 8 bit encodings
but no hardware player can play such files.
			</Text>
			<Recommended>disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>disabled</Default>
		</encoder10bit>
	</Codec>
	<Form name="PresetImporter">
		<presetList name="info">
			<Text>To import all presets in once, right click on this list and select all...</Text>
		</presetList>
	</Form>
	<Form name="PresetExporter">
		<presetList name="info">
			<Text>To export all presets in once, right click on this list and select all...</Text>
		</presetList>
	</Form>
	<Form name="SettingsForm">
		<alwaysmuxmkv name="Alway mux mkv video encoding with mkvmerge">
			<Text>
If no additional streams are to mux this setting defines if the x264 encoder will output
the encoding directly in the mkv container format (non/slow seekable) or if it will be
muxed with mkvmerge.
			</Text>
		</alwaysmuxmkv>
		<ffmsthreads name="FFMS thread count">
			<Text>
The number of decoding threads to request from ffms. Setting it to less than or equal to zero 
means it defaults to the number of logical CPU's reported by Windows. 
Note that a value not equal to 1 may lead to crashes.
Recommended Value: 1
			</Text>
		</ffmsthreads>
		<useituvalues name="Use ITU aspect ratio">
			<Text>
When enabled the aspect ratio of DVD sources (720x480, 720x576) will be shown and calculated as ITU values.
When disabled clear 4:3 or 16:9 is used.
			</Text>
		</useituvalues>
	</Form>
</ContextHelp>